# **Michael Barbone**

1334 72<sup>nd</sup> Street, Brooklyn, NY, 11228 Phone: (973)-557-5578 Email: michael.barbone@gmail.com

I am a Full Stack Developer with experience building websites and web applications. I specialize in the MERN stack and have an unwavering passion for creating software. My goal is to write clean, DRY, and reuse-able code while always keeping user experience in mind.

## #Skills

Front-End **Back End Source Control FrameWorks** UI/UX Javascript ES6 / jQuery Node.is Git React / Redux Wireframing / UML Github CSS / SASS **Express Bootstrap** Atomic Design HTML MongoDB/Mongoose **User Stories** Jira MySQL/Sequelize SCRUM / Agile Handlebars

Webpack RESTful APIs

508 Accessibility Jest

Enzyme

# **#Professional Experience**

#### **MELTWATER**

Business Analyst | New York, New York | June 2016 - Current

- Provide mission critical data to improve NY Client Success efficiency and results
- Work closely with upper management to develop and drive strategic and tactical initiatives related to client retention and growth
- Construct and maintain all NY Client Success resources and documents
- Create new solutions to further engage clients and improve client relations
- Analyze product sales & usage data to identify new opportunities
- Work closely with clients to assist in account set up, development, and ad-hoc reporting

#### **MFITWATFR**

Sales Development Representative | New York, New York | February 2016 - June 2016

- Prospected potential clients through extensive market research.
- Exceed KPI's while surpassing individual and team quotas
- Established productive relationships with key decision makers
- Logged activity into Meltwater's CRM in order to strengthen client relationships
- Emphasized product features based on analysis of customers' needs

### KALENDRIA

Business Sales Representative | Dubai, UAE | August 2016 - December 2016

- Responsible for developing a portfolio of accounts through new business development and market research
- Present the business model and train new clients on Kalendria's website and service
- Gather, organize, and analyze data about Dubai market trends in a wide range of consumer services in order to increase customer outreach and site traffic
- Administrator of Kalendria's social media accounts and organized social media promotions and campaigns

### QUENCH USA

Information Technology Assistant | King of Prussia, Pennsylvania | May 2014 - September 2014

- Executed daily updates to Accounts Receivable report for Quench's CRM system
- Performed daily audit of Quench's ERP platform to ensure data accuracy
- Monitored data exchange between Quench's CRM and ERP systems

## #Education

**Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey** | Sep 2011 – May 2015: New Brunswick, New Jersey Bachelor of Science, Political Science

- Gamma Sigma Alpha National Greek Academic Honor Society Member
- Academic Excellence Award

**Columbia University** | New York, New York | Jan 2019 - July 2019 Executive Education Certificate in Web

### #Patent

## **Retractable Gripping Apparatus for Walking Assistance Devices**

- Inventor & Owner of United States Patent Application 20130092201
- Creator of all designs & responsible for collaborating efforts with patent lawyers and engineers